- Previously on Gotham...
- Uncle Frank. Maybe you want to tell me
where the hell you've
been since I was a kid.
FRANK: The Court is a secret society.
If it's so secret, how
do you know about them?
Your father and I were both members.
GORDON: It was a drunk driver!
I watched him die.
My brother was making trouble
and they killed him.
(gasps)
One cannot deny love.
(gunshot)
I... don't... love you.
Look who's alive.
I just remembered.
There's someone I need to kill.
- KATHRYN: The clone is in place.
- FRANK: What about Bruce Wayne?
KATHRYN: He should be
waking up as we speak.
FALCONE: I've always done whatever
the Court has asked of me.
What aren't you telling me?
This city is on the brink of chaos.
Seems like judgment came to
Gotham earlier than expected.
Members of the Ruling Council,
Gotham has fallen ill.
Violence and crime continue to spread
like an unstoppable disease.
Drastic action must be taken.
To that end, a weapon is being built.
A weapon intended to
be unleashed on Gotham
so that the city may be
cleansed and rebuilt by us.
The Head of our Court asks that we reach
a unanimous vote to proceed.
♪ ♪
KATHRYN: Judgment has been passed.
Gotham must fall.
- sync and corrections by Mr. C -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(door closes in distance)
I want to speak with
whoever's in charge.
That would be me.
Is the Court of Owls
behind my abduction?
The Court is a tool. Nothing more.
You won't get away with this.
People will know I'm gone.
We've taken precautions
to ensure your absence
won't be noticed.
My clone.
He's in Gotham pretending
to be me, isn't he?
Alfred will figure it out.
Perhaps.
But by that time,
I'm hoping we've accomplished our goal.
Which is what?
I need your help, Bruce.
Eat.
You're going to need your strength.
We'll begin soon.
REPORTER: Aubrey James, the once and...
All right, come on people, come on.
Let's get back to work.
Joe, shut that off.
Can you believe this nonsense?
After all that's said and
done, who's back in charge?
Aubrey James. The
original crook himself.
How was the cabin?
What?
You and your uncle. You must've
had a lot to catch up on.
Oh, yeah.
Any word on Nygma?
No. But after gassing the cadets
and dangling me over an empty stairwell,
he just disappeared.
No riddles, puzzles or
singing telegrams, yet.
Who's, uh, "Michael Ness"?
(sighs) The drunk driver who
hit and killed my father
when I was nine.
Something my uncle said got me thinking.
- What do you got?
- Not much.
He was convicted of
vehicular manslaughter.
Got six years.
Then got his ticket punched in a
prison stabbing a few months in.
Silver lining.
Yeah.
But I pulled his medical
file from Blackgate,
found something that wasn't
in the original case file.
He had "chronic persistent hepatitis."
I was gonna ask Lee what
it was when she got in.
Chronic persistent hepatitis
is a non-progressive form
of liver inflammation.
How do you know that?
You kidding? It's known
as the Irish Curse.
With chronic inflammation,
you cannot drink. Nothing, not a drop.
Not even beer.
Well, this guy didn't get the memo.
His blood alcohol
was off the charts the
night of the accident.
You're not hearing me.
If this guy had chronic
liver inflammation,
if he blew a 0.1
on a blood alcohol test,
he'd be dead before he
got behind the wheel.
If that's true, then someone
dummied the report.
Can you do some digging?
Find out who this guy was?
Sure, but... Hey.
Where you going?
Ta-da!
Pretty cool, huh?
I told you the whole estate
was abandoned... can you believe it?
- As a matter of fact, I can.
- You know,
the fresh air will do you good.
It smells like rotting death in here.
- Oh. I think someone's hungry.
- What are you doing? Stop it!
I... told you I am fine!
I am a grown man, for crying out loud!
(singsongy): And you're hungry.
(giggling)
Ah...
What's with you and all the plants?
Oh, they're my friends.
Your friends?
- Yeah.
- (quietly): Wonderful.
You know, plants make better
friends than most people.
And some of them helped save your life.
It's broth.
I even put in some white
willow for your fever.
(mug shatters)
- What is wrong with you?
- For the millionth time,
I need to get back to Gotham!
What's the rush?!
I was betrayed and shot.
I should be plotting my
revenge, building an army,
not drinking pinecone juice
with the... crazy plant lady.
So build an army. No one's stopping you.
And I could even help
if you weren't being
such a jerk.
Jerk.
Fine.
I need you to deliver a message
to Gabe.
Who's Gabe?
He's a moron.
But... he is a loyal moron.
And every army starts
with one single loyal soldier.
"Please."
(whispering): Please?
Okay.
Fine.
Thank you for meeting me.
Why here?
It's public, open,
easy to spot if anyone's watching us.
The driver who hit my father's
car that night wasn't drunk.
I think he did it on purpose,
and someone made it
look like an accident.
Easy enough for the Court.
So let's say I believe you.
What do you want from me?
I have just learned something
I am still having trouble believing.
A weapon is en route, headed for Gotham.
A weapon the Court intends
to use to destroy the city.
What are you talking about?
You said the Court controls Gotham.
Why would they want to destroy it?
This isn't the Court as a whole.
It's limited to a number
of high-ranking members,
fanatics who believe the
city needs to be cleansed.
And you really think
they're capable of this?
They've done it before.
Twice in the city's history
they've laid waste to Gotham.
It's no bluff.
So how do we stop it?
I have no idea.
I don't even know what the weapon is.
But that's exactly what
I'm going to find out.
- I can help.
- No. The Court knows
I reached out to you, but that's all.
We need to keep it that way,
in case I'm discovered.
Be careful, Uncle Frank.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to intrude.
I saw you earlier.
Who was that man you were with?
My Uncle Frank.
I thought you two were estranged.
We recently reconnected.
Good for you.
(Thompkins sighs) I've
been coming here a lot.
The other day I saw this...
little old man, must
have been in his 90s,
all dressed up,
standing in front of his wife's grave...
smiling.
I couldn't understand what
there was to smile about.
And then it occurred to me.
They shared a whole life together.
I'm sorry.
How do you do that?
How do you just... move on,
leaving so much
destruction in your wake?
I wish I could do that.
(phone buzzing)
- Yeah?
- BULLOCK: Hey.
That driver that hit and
killed your father that night
was a career scumbag.
What'd you find out?
He did a stretch for grand theft auto,
among other things, and get this...
the high-priced lawyer
who got him his plea
was paid for by none other
than Carmine Falcone.
- (laughing)
- (strained): Okay, that's... easy. Okay.
Okay, that's enough.
(grunts, laughs)
Oh, Boss, I can't believe it.
You know that everyone
thinks you're dead.
- Yes.
- And that Barbara's running things?
Gabe, this might go faster
if you just listen.
I need to build an army
to exact my revenge,
and to take back my throne.
Will you help me?
Of course I will. When the guys hear
that you're still alive,
they'll come running.
I'll make sure of it.
What do you want me to do?
That.
I want you to do that, Gabe.
Right. I got it.
No problem.
Hey...
Um... there's something off about him.
No argument there.
I don't trust him.
Gabe?
He's a human Labrador. You
whistle, he comes running.
Trust me, he's loyal.
I have this perfume.
One whiff, and a man
will do anything I ask.
Including telling the truth.
Look, now that Gabe is here,
I'm afraid this is where we part ways.
I have an army to build,
a war to plan,
and we really do not know
each other that well.
You understand.
No.
Maybe you can ask one of your plants.
I do not trust you.
I saved your life.
My men are on their way.
You trust him?
But I...
I thought we were friends.
(snorts) Friends?
(chuckling): Friends.
Oh.
You're being serious.
Look, don't take this the wrong way,
but you are a bit of a freak.
(door opens, closes)
Did she tell you not to trust me?
Yeah.
Why?
Smart girl.
♪ ♪
Shall we begin?
The temple is some sort
of maze, is that it?
Everything is a maze, Bruce.
The only difference
is whether we realize
our place within it.
Given enough time, I
will find a way out.
How much time?
How long have you been blindly
running down the corridors
of your life only to end
up in the same place?
It's time to pick a direction.
You can speak in cryptic
riddles all you want.
I'm not scared of you.
But you are scared of
something, aren't you?
Sit.
Let me show you what I have to offer.
You have some nerve showing up here.
We need to talk. Alone.
No, we don't.
You took my son from me.
And you took my father away from me.
I'd say that makes us even.
Your father was killed
by a drunk driver.
No, he wasn't.
The driver wasn't drunk.
He hit us on purpose.
But I think you know that because
you paid for his lawyer.
Still think we have
nothing to talk about?
If you have a question for me, son...
why not go ahead and ask it?
Did you order the hit on my father?
No.
I respected your father.
Much more than the son he left behind.
But someone did.
It was a hit?
Yes.
The Court of Owls.
What do you know about them?
I know my uncle is a member.
- Are you?
- No.
But we've built a
partnership which has been
mutually beneficial over the years.
You mean you do their bidding.
Everyone does the Court's bidding.
Some of us just know it.
The person who came to you...
a member of the Court?
Yes.
Who was it?
Who ordered the hit on my father?
I want a name.
Frank Gordon.
Your uncle.
(door closes)
Hello, Jim.
Thought we could use a drink.
Is it true?
Did you order the hit on my father?
Carmine called the Court after you left.
You shouldn't have gone there.
It'll raise suspicions.
Is it true?
Yes.
Why?
I already told you...
your father was determined
to expose the Court
and became a risk.
Simple as that.
So you had him killed?
Your own brother?
You want to shoot me, Jim?
You'd be doing me a favor.
But it won't change anything.
The only thing we can do now
is finish what Peter started
and bring down the Court.
It's what he would have wanted.
What my father would have wanted
is for justice to be done.
So do I.
Frank Gordon, you're under arrest
for the murder of Peter Gordon.
Turn around.
Turn around!
Have you not been listening?
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you
- in a court of law.
- Arrest me
- and it's over.
- You have the right to an attorney.
Stopping them is the
only thing that matters.
- My father mattered!
- (sighs)
(grunts)
Dock 9C.
It's where the weapon will be arriving.
It's all I've been able to find out.
I need to speak with the
Court, try to buy some time.
You need to find out when the
weapon will be arriving,
and you need to do it without the Court
finding out you're involved.
Otherwise... we're both dead.
Make a choice, Jim.
(door opens, closes)
I didn't think you had it in you.
I know.
You never did.
Oh, boo-hoo.
Is that what this is about?
No one gave you a gold
star for thuggery?
If you're gonna kill me,
then get on with it already.
I ain't gonna kill you.
We're gonna auction off that right
to the highest bidder.
(car approaches outside)
We?
That would be my sales force.
(car doors open)
If he had just listened to me, but no.
Nobody listens to Ivy...
(sighs)
BULLOCK: Whoa.
That's a lot to take in.
Tell me about it.
A secret organization that
controls all of Gotham?
If that's true, somebody should tell 'em
they're doing a pretty terrible job.
He told you all this at the cabin?
Most of it. The weapon
intended to destroy the city...
that's a new wrinkle
he threw at me today.
Quite the family reunion you're having.
I didn't mean to involve
you in all this,
I just don't know who to trust anymore.
Way I see it, as hard as it was
to hear what Falcone had to say,
at least he confirmed the
existence of the Court.
So I take my uncle at his word?
You work the lead.
Check the docks. But that's just me.
I tend to give apocalyptic warnings
of mass destruction the
benefit of the doubt.
But it wasn't my father who was killed.
So if you want to go after
your uncle for what he did,
I got your back.
He says the Court has destroyed the city
twice before in its history.
We can't take that chance.
I'll call Judge Bam Bam, get a warrant.
We'll hit the docks and start
kicking in doors today.
No. He was very clear.
The Court can't know
I'm looking into this. The
GCPD cannot be involved.
So who do we know who can raid the docks
who won't raise questions
and isn't connected to the GCPD?
No. No, no, no, no, no.
♪ ♪
♪ Love hurts ♪
♪ Love scars ♪
Hmm.
Feels a little light.
And, you know...
Mommy's gonna need
a new pair of stilettos.
♪ Take a lot of pain ♪
Capisce?
(grunts)
♪ It holds a lot of rain ♪
Who's next?
(phone rings)
♪ Love hurts ♪
Barbara Queen.
♪ Ooh, love hurts ♪
Jim,
what an unpleasant surprise.
Let me guess,
do I hear a favor coming on?
I've been waiting a long time
for you to begin your journey.
The only journey I'm going
to take is back home.
Back to Gotham.
Then we share the same destination.
What are those?
Acupuncture needles?
Of a sort.
Think of them as keys.
A way to open the mind to that
which it locks away, even from itself.
What are the symbols on the ends?
♪ ♪
(distant traffic sounds)
You said you wanted to return to Gotham.
Here we are.
(horns honking in distance)
(laughter)
Oh, come on, Tom.
- It wasn't that bad.
- Oh, no?
Childish drivel.
MARTHA: I thought the acting was
fine, the music was lovely.
What about you, Bruce?
Sorry, Mom, I agree with Dad.
- It was kinda lame.
- (groans)
THOMAS: "Kinda lame"?
- There's no such word as "kinda."
- (laughter)
- Dad?
Mom?
Give me your money!
- (gunshot)
- (gasps)
(gasping)
How'd you... how'd you do that?
How did you do that?
What was that place?
- A memory.
- No.
(shudders) No, it was real.
The mind can do
far more than recall memories.
If one knows how, you
can experience them,
relive them as if they were
happening for the first time.
You're saying we were inside my mind?
One is always inside their own mind.
Pretending we are separate from it,
that is the falsehood.
Why would you show me that?
Why would you take me back there?
You've never left that alley, Bruce.
Not really.
And for you to be able
to accept what it is
I have to teach, you need to.
Rest.
We'll try again soon.
(ship horn blows)
(groaning)
(chuckles)
Torture is fun.
However, I need to know
what is coming into dock 9C.
I told you, there is no dock 9C.
- I can't tell you what I don't...
- What you don't know.
Yes, I've heard that one.
Now tell me something I haven't heard.
You don't know what they're capable of.
Even when Don Falcone
was running things,
he never asked questions
about what came into 9C.
In case you haven't heard,
Don Falcone ain't running things, baby.
- Now, what is coming...
- (groaning)
into dock 9C?
Something already came in last week,
- but they picked it up. Okay?
- Oh?
The crate, it's still over there.
I swear, that's all I know.
I swear.
So, you must have a phone number
to alert them when things arrive.
Huh? What do you say
we give 'em a little call?
'Cause I would love an introduction.
- (clang)
- (wings flapping)
- (metal blade ringing)
- (man screams)
Get him!
(automatic gunfire)
I-I swear,
I didn't tell her nothin'!
GABE: Make sure you get
him from all sides.
Potential bidders need to know
that he's alive and well.
Once we get these delivered,
the auction can begin.
Forgot these in the car.
Cannolis from Alberto's, boss.
Thank God. I'm starved.
Alberto's are my favorite...
Looks like you got yourself
into quite the pickle.
You're sitting right next to me.
I think our fates are
somewhat intertwined.
Oh, no. I'll be fine.
What? What are you talking about?
Totally fine.
If you have a plan, tell me.
Tell me.
What? You want me to beg? Is that it?
I want you to be nice to me.
Nice to you?
Yes! Is that so much to ask?
No.
No, it's not.
Okay, I'll be nice. I promise.
Now, what is your plan?
Lay it on me.
Watch and learn.
Oh, yoo-hoo. Canolli guy.
Hey, quick question.
If I had information,
like, really good information
that would get you a ton
more money for Penguin,
would you let me go?
I don't know. Maybe.
What is it?
Oh, I can't tell you in front of...
Let me whisper it in your ear.
Do you like my perfume?
(inhales)
You'll do anything I ask?
Super.
Kill them all.
(gunshots)
Wait!
Stop!
Get his gun.
Grab the gun!
(chuckling)
Give it to me.
Give it to him!
And tell him to untie us.
Untie us!
You don't have to yell.
(giggles) Sorry.
I just got so caught up in the moment.
(gunshot)
You know,
I like the idea of an auction, Gabe.
I think I'll auction you off to myself.
Piece by bloody piece.
(distant traffic sounds)
Carmine told us Jim came to him
asking questions about
his father's death.
What exactly does he know?
Only what Carmine knew.
That I gave the order
to have Peter killed.
Nothing can lead back to the Court.
After all these years,
why would he start
looking into this now?
I don't know. Believe me, this
is the last thing I wanted.
Which is why I'm here.
I know my nephew.
Jim won't stop until one of us is dead.
Unfortunate.
He would have made a powerful
ally in what lies ahead.
In that case,
you know what you have to do.
James Gordon must be killed.
- Barbara called.
- What'd she say?
Apparently, dock 9C is being guarded
by a blade-wielding psychopath
who almost killed them.
Of course it is. Did she find
out if anything was coming in?
That's the thing,
it already has.
I thought your uncle said the weapon
wasn't in the city yet. He did.
Which means either he's
lying or he didn't know.
Either way, we have to assume
the Court already has it.
- We still don't even know what "it" is.
- We know one thing.
Barbara said the crate that she saw
was stamped with Indian Hill.
So something from the freak factory
is gonna wipe out the city?
(phone buzzing)
Gordon.
FRANK: We need to talk.
Did you know the weapon is here?
What? No.
What the hell is going on, Frank?
We're running out of time.
I'm at my house.
Come alone and come quickly.
(phone clicks)
(panting)
I trusted you, Gabe.
And how did you repay that loyalty?
Betrayal.
Not for nothing,
but I was there after
your mother was killed
when no one else was.
And how'd you repay me?
By passing me over.
Wow.
A valid point.
Perhaps we forget that loyalty
must be extended before
it can be returned.
Yeah.
You were loyal to me once, Gabe.
I wonder, could you be again?
Yes! Oh, boss.
I'd swear an oath on my dead
mother's grave right now.
God rest her soul.
No need for anything so dramatic.
Ivy, would you mind ensuring
that Gabe's oath of loyalty
is noble and true?
If what is what now?
Make him smell your perfume.
Right. Okay.
(sniffing)
Um, raise your right hand.
Do you swear
to be loyal and true to Penguin?
No.
Ouch.
I don't understand. Why not?
Why can't he be loyal?
Go ahead, answer.
I never was.
I only followed you out of fear.
We all did.
Actually, I can live with that.
Fear and respect... management 101.
No one ever respected you.
We always saw you for
what you really are.
A tiny freak who used
to hold an umbrella.
Nothing more.
A freak?
A... freak?
A freak?!
No!
A freak!
A freak! A freak!
(laughing)
(Oswald yelling, blows landing)
(yelling echoing)
(door closes)
Thanks for coming.
The weapon the Court is planning
to use on Gotham came from Indian Hill.
Any idea what it might be?
No.
Like I said, I had no idea
that it had already arrived.
It's clear that the Court
no longer trusts me.
Then why call me down here?
I'm supposed to kill you.
Which leaves us... where?
That's up to you.
I need someone to replace
me on the Court.
Someone who can find
out what the weapon is
and how to stop it.
Someone I can trust.
You need to join the Court of Owls, Jim.
It's the only way.
You just said they want me dead.
They still want you on the Court.
They just don't seen
now how it's possible,
but I do.
At some point, a woman named
Kathryn is going to call
to ask if you are dead.
And when she does,
I suggest you pick up.
And tell her what?
That you blame me for
your father's death.
I gave the order to have him killed,
and I deserved what I got.
What are you talking about?
You have his strength, Jim.
You can finish what he started.
For both of us.
He would have been so proud of you.
No!
(thud, door creaks and whirs open)
(Bruce grunts)
(Bruce groaning)
Please! Please. I'm sorry.
I'll do whatever you want.
Just please don't make me go back there!
Give me your money!
(groans, thuds)
(gasps)
No!
(grunting)
(wind whipping, grunts)
(yells)
(gasps)
(groans)
(panting)
I have so much to teach you, Bruce.
But your pain...
it blocks you from who
I need you to become.
Who Gotham needs you to become.
(gasps loudly)
(panting)
If one's feelings and
emotions are strong enough,
their consequences can follow
you back into the real world.
I don't know what you want from me.
Over the centuries, we've
tried to end the cycle
of crime and violence
that plagues Gotham,
only for it to start up again.
And do you know why it does?
People are afraid.
And fear breeds hopelessness.
I'm supposed to believe you care
about the people of Gotham?
I do.
Very much.
Which is where you come in.
Gotham needs something I believe
only you can provide.
What?
A protector, Bruce.
I can't protect Gotham.
Not by myself. No one can.
Perhaps.
But if you were to become a symbol,
a symbol against fear,
then Gotham can be reborn.
Okay, I admit it.
I might have lost my
temper there a little bit.
Sorry about that.
It's okay.
I don't know why I let him get to me.
Sticks and stones, right?
Hmm.
Words always hurt me way
more than sticks or stones.
Yeah. Me, too.
So does this mean you're giving
up your plans for revenge?
I can't take on Nygma and Barbara
and the rest of them by myself.
Who said anything about
taking them on by yourself?
Selina told me some pretty crazy stories
about people she met
down in Indian Hill.
Said you wanted to build an army, right?
Well,
what about an army of freaks?
What kind of freaks?
(phone ringing)
(phone beeps on)
Kathryn, I presume.
KATHRYN: Detective Gordon.
I can't say I'm entirely surprised.
I killed my uncle.
I make no apologies for it.
We understand.
Good. Maybe it's time we meet.
Agreed.
(click, dial tone)
www.tvsubtitles.net